<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zelda on bury the hammer</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/zelda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zelda on bury the hammer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 12:14:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/zelda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zelda: Link&#39;s Awakening</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/zelda-links-awakening/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 12:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/zelda-links-awakening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zelda has a tradition of having a main game followed by a weird offshoot. The main game will talk about the Triforce, defeating Ganon, et cetera. The weird offshoot generally does whatever it likes. Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening is the first weird offshoot in the series.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unless you count Zelda II, which is more bad than weird.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening actually has an interesting plot, for one. You collect the macguffins, you beat the final boss. But everything has this dreamy, surreal Twin Peaks vibe. There’s a dungeon themed around a face (?!). There&amp;rsquo;s an existential plot twist. There are.. Mario references everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelda: A Link to the Past</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/zelda-a-link-to-the-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/zelda-a-link-to-the-past/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike the previous Zelda games, I have a history with Link to the Past. When my parents relented and bought me a second hand SNES, it came with a few games - one was LTTP. Out of all the games I had, it was my favourite, and I played it a LOT. Replaying it as an adult brings back very specific memories.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Out of Zelda or Zelda II, it’s clear that Nintendo saw that the first was the template to follow. This game uses the template of the first Zelda and improves every single facet. The 16 bit pixel art is BEAUTIFUL. Hyrule is finally a fleshed out world, full of character. The map &lt;em&gt;feels&lt;/em&gt; like a condensed world with distinct areas, and tells a story by itself. Dungeons are intricate and clever, and have overarching themes and puzzles. Exploration is always rewarded, and heaps of fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelda II: The Adventure of Link</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/zelda-ii-the-adventure-of-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/zelda-ii-the-adventure-of-link/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zelda 2 is pretty famous for being the worst Zelda. It’s also famous for being obnoxiously hard.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obnoxious is probably the right word, too. This isn’t Dark Souls style “tough but fair” masochism, this is straight up unfairness. One enemy, the iron knuckle, will probably kill you from full health unless you use an obscure technique to attack them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because Zelda 2 was only the second in the series, they decided to drastically depart from the formula laid down in the first one - much like how Super Mario Bros. 2 outside Japan is very different. Zelda 2 has a lives system, combat is side scrolling, there’s an overhead world map, random encounters, and an XP/levelling system. None of these have ever been seen since.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Legend of Zelda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-legend-of-zelda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-legend-of-zelda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to do something a bit weird, which is play through all the Zelda games. In er, order. And write about them as I go.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which means the first one is Legend of Zelda, for the NES.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Legend of Zelda is surprisingly like Dark Souls: zero help, high difficulty, full of secrets. It is nowhere near as fair, though. Nintendo’s idea of difficulty towards the end often involves putting lots of enemies in a room. Blue darknuts and wizzrobes are particularly aggravating. The worst of all is the Like Like, though. If one touches you, you lose your upgraded shield permanently. It costs 130 rupees to replace. In future games you’d get back your shield as soon as you defeat it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
