<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
	<channel>
		<title>Matt Long</title>
		<description>
			
				Matt Long&#39;s homepage
			
		</description>
		<link>http://www.burythehammer.com</link>
		<atom:link href="http://www.burythehammer.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>My favourite albums of 2015</title>
				
					<category>music></category>
				
				<description>I always used to write about music, but I stopped (reasons: complicated). I’m going to write a bit here about what I liked this year, though. I’m not pretending to be comprehensive. Or even that knowledgeable. But I know what I’ve enjoyed.

</description>
				<image>
					<url>http://www.w3schools.com/images/logo.gif</url>
					<title></title>
					<link>/img/thumbnails/</link>
				</image>
				<content type="html">
					
					<p>I always used to write about music, but I stopped (reasons: complicated). I’m going to write a bit here about what I liked this year, though. I’m not pretending to be comprehensive. Or even that knowledgeable. But I know what I’ve enjoyed.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="grimes---art-angels">Grimes - Art Angels</h2>
<p>Grimes has taken her quirky brand of experimental pop and made it mainstream. I literally cannot stop listening to it. It’s catchy, it’s quirky, it’s danceable - pop at its very best. The kind of album I find myself dancing to, late at night, drunk. There are so many great songs on here, it’s hard to know where to start. <em>Butterfly</em> and <em>Realiti</em> are my picks, but I could listen to any song. It’s great. So great.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="joanna-gruesome---peanut-butter">Joanna Gruesome - Peanut Butter</h2>

<p>I once very drunkenly talked with one of Joanna Gruesome at Field Day a few years ago. I was probably a douche (I am a douche ordinarily, so alcohol probably didn’t help). I also hadn’t listened to them at all by that point, which is a shame for me, because they’re fantastic. <em>Weird Sister</em> was a wonderful album, and this is just as good.</p>

<p>I still can’t remember who it was I bonded with that day, to my eternal shame.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="courtney-barnett---sometimes-i-sit-and-think-and-sometimes-i-just-sit">Courtney Barnett - Sometimes I sit and think, and sometimes I just sit.</h2>

<p>I went to Australia this year for the wedding of two of my favourite people. This is an album that got mentioned a lot by the two of them. I was assured that Courtney was a big thing there - and now, I see why. Exactly the kind of lyrical texture and down to earth themes that I like from Allo Darlin’, except with a bitter, deadpan twist. There’s incredible wit in those lyrics.</p>

<p>(as a side note, almost nobody there has heard of The Lucksmiths, so get your listening habits in order, Australia.)</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="new-order---music-complete">New Order - Music Complete</h2>

<p>I grew up with New Order, so you’d think I was biased, and you’re right. I thought this was going to be awful. Peter Hook (their star bassist) has left, their last couple of efforts have been very variable, so it was a massive surprise to me how good this album turned out. Gillian Gilbert - who has been absent since their reform in 2001 - is a silent credit here, and they’re far better at doing electronic pop music than the guitary indie that Hook was driving the band towards. <em>Tutti Frutti</em> sounds cheesy at first, but has an amazingly catchy chorus, and <em>Restless</em> is every bit as endearing as <em>Regret</em>, at least to my ears.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="haiku-salut---etch-and-etch-deep">Haiku Salut - Etch and Etch Deep</h2>
<p>If there was ever such a thing as twee post rock, this would be it. If anything though, that label is selling them short. This is a wonderful, touching album. My only regret is that I didn’t get into them sooner and saw more of their live stuff.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="kurt-vile---blieve-im-goin-down">Kurt Vile - B’lieve I’m Goin Down</h2>
<p>This is a good album. Okay, so it’s not as good as <em>Wakin’ on a Pretty Daze</em>. Few things are. It’s still a good album, if a little inconsistent. I don’t think the dreamy hazy stuff works as well, but <em>Pretty Pimpin’</em> is one of the best pop songs I’ve heard from Kurt.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="cheatahs---mythologies">Cheatahs - Mythologies</h2>
<p>Who? What? I like Cheatahs a lot, they’re not especially well known though. Shoegaze-y instrumental bollocks. Consistently great. If I was better at writing about music, I’d be able to write more, but y’know, deal with it.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="belle--sebastian---girls-in-peacetime-want-to-dance">Belle &amp; Sebastian - Girls in Peacetime Want to Dance</h2>
<p>Poor old Belle &amp; Sebastian, forever living in the shadow of the fact they’ve written some of the best pop albums of all time. They still crank out great stuff though (if again, they’re inconsistent). Nobody’s Empire deserves to be recognised as one of their all time greats - tender, well paced, catchy, yet defiantly lacking a chorus.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="the-mountain-goats---beat-the-champ">The Mountain Goats - Beat the Champ</h2>
<p>I feel like I’m compensating for not knowing enough about The Mountain Goats. They’re a fun band but I never put the effort in. Beat The Champ has a belter right near the start: The Legend of Chavo Guerrero, a tale about his favourite Mexican wrestler when growing up. I feel like the album never quite lives up to the high this sets, but it’s still a great listen.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="jeffery-lewis--los-bolts---manhattan">Jeffery Lewis &amp; Los Bolts - Manhattan</h2>
<p>For too long, an artist I refused to get. I even saw half his set (with the Junkyard) at Indietracks and just didn’t understand it. Something I find frustrating, as I try to abide by the philosophy that if I don’t ‘get’ something subjective, it’s my fault. Still, this album is pretty great. Funny and incisive at times (Support Tours is basically a far more detailed and bitter Silver Dollars), totally absurd at others (why is The Pigeon so stereotypically Jewish?).</p>
>
				</content>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 15:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.burythehammer.com/blog/favourite-albums-2015</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.burythehammer.com/blog/favourite-albums-2015</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Fallout hacking minigame script</title>
				
					<category>coding></category>
				
				<description>The password cracking minigame on Fallout is so annoying, I made a little script to help you do it.

</description>
				<image>
					<url>http://www.w3schools.com/images/logo.gif</url>
					<title></title>
					<link>/img/thumbnails/</link>
				</image>
				<content type="html">
					
					<p>The password cracking minigame on Fallout is so annoying, I made a little script to help you do it.</p>

<p>It’s because I’ve been playing Fallout: New Vegas for the first time recently. Lots of my friends are playing Fallout 4, which I’m not all that excited by - but I thought I’d play New Vegas instead, because I really like Obsidian Entertainment. It may be mostly because one of their founders is Chris Avellone, who was the principal designer of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planescape%3A_Torment">Planescape Torment</a>, one of my favourite games of all time.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.stack.imgur.com/ckL1M.jpg" alt="Image Alt" /></p>

<p>Anyway, Fallout 3 and Fallout: New Vegas both have this little minigame you have to do every time you want to ‘hack’ a terminal, because of course computers let anybody access root if you do a trivial little word game. It’s very annoying, not much fun, and way better done by a script. So I wrote one.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/burythehammer/fallout-password-checker">You can find it on Github here</a>, along with the instructions on how to use it.</p>

<p>I am sadly aware that it probably would have been quicker to use a pen and paper than spend an hour writing this.</p>

<p>~ Matt</p>
>
				</content>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 23:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.burythehammer.com/blog/fallout-password-helper</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.burythehammer.com/blog/fallout-password-helper</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Testing With Microservices</title>
				
					<category>testing></category>
				
					<category>opencredo></category>
				
				<description>I’ve got some free, non-billable time at the moment at work, so they’ve let me do a bit of research and development, as well as some technical blog posts.

</description>
				<image>
					<url>http://www.w3schools.com/images/logo.gif</url>
					<title></title>
					<link>/img/thumbnails/</link>
				</image>
				<content type="html">
					
					<p>I’ve got some free, non-billable time at the moment at work, so they’ve let me do a bit of research and development, as well as some technical blog posts.</p>

<p>I can’t reproduce them here (they’re written on company time, so it’s fair enough they have it exclusively on their site), but it feels silly not to link over to any stuff I do.</p>

<p>For my first post, I’ve written about my work on the Sedex Advance project. I started pretty much as soon as I joined OpenCredo, and I was impressed by the technical wizardry they had employed. Some of the advanced architectural design we used impacted my work as a tester, so I’ve written up my reflections on what kind of difficulties we had, and the kind of techniques we used to combat them. It’s also, from a tester’s perspective, a good introduction to the architecture if you’ve not encountered it before.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.opencredo.com/2015/11/11/testing-with-microservices/">Testing with Microservices</a></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>[Microservices is a] great architectural style when implemented correctly. However, microservices bring inherent operational complexity, which you can’t ignore, and your testing strategy will have to reflect this.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>~ Matt</p>
>
				</content>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 18:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.burythehammer.com/blog/testing-with-microservices</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.burythehammer.com/blog/testing-with-microservices</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Reading List</title>
				
					<category>reading></category>
				
					<category>politics></category>
				
					<category>meta></category>
				
				<description>I read a lot. Here are the things I read.

</description>
				<image>
					<url>http://www.w3schools.com/images/logo.gif</url>
					<title></title>
					<link>/img/thumbnails/</link>
				</image>
				<content type="html">
					
					<p>I read a lot. Here are the things I read.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.economist.com/">The Economist</a></li>
</ul>

<p>My main dose of current affairs. There’s almost never fluff pieces, and I find the weekly newsmagazine format suits my habits a lot more than a daily newspaper. Their science &amp; technology section is also genuinely excellent.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.private-eye.co.uk/">Private Eye</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Most people start reading Private Eye for the cartoons, and then realise they do some of the best investigative journalism in the UK. Rotten Boroughs and In The Back are full of important stuff that everyone should read.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://arstechnica.co.uk/">Ars Technica</a></li>
</ul>

<p>The best of the bunch as far as tech websites go. Probably not nearly as developer based as I would like. Their UK site has been championing an anti-survelliance agenda at the moment, which I’m quite impressed by.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.rockpapershotgun.com/">Rock Paper Shotgun</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Above all else, the best thing about RPS is that they treat videogames as a medium rather than a weird hobby. I trust their opinion on PC games more than anywhere else. Talk a lot about smaller, independent games.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/">GamaSutra</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Significantly more technical and usually cover the game creation process rather than reviewing the finished product. Their blog section is excellent.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://littlewhitelies.co.uk/">Little White Lies</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Often pretentious, but I have yet to find another site whose taste in films I share more. They review a lot of movies outside the mainstream I’d have never heard of otherwise.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.qwantz.com/">Dinosaur Comics</a></li>
</ul>

<p>I’m pretty sure I learned more from Dinosaur Comics when I was a student than I did from my actual physics course. Ryan North also writes the excellent Adventure Time comics series.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.thedailymash.co.uk/">Daily Mash</a> / <a href="http://www.newsthump.com/">NewsThump</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Where better to learn about what’s happening in the mainstream media than something that mocks it relentlessly?</p>
>
				</content>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 12:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.burythehammer.com/blog/reading-list</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.burythehammer.com/blog/reading-list</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Beginnings</title>
				
					<category>meta></category>
				
				<description>In a last ditch effort to attempt to be professional about something, I’ve relaunched this blog.

</description>
				<image>
					<url>http://www.w3schools.com/images/logo.gif</url>
					<title></title>
					<link>/img/thumbnails/</link>
				</image>
				<content type="html">
					
					<p>In a last ditch effort to attempt to be professional about something, I’ve relaunched this blog.</p>

<p>Originally this was a blog about music, specifically indiepop music, with a focus on gigs. With a bit of photography thrown in. My aims with this relaunch are somewhat more professionally oriented (I work in tech, but more on that later), but there’ll probably be plenty of personal stuff on here too.</p>

<p>I’ve chosen to move the tech stack of the blog to be something far cleaner and more lightweight. I’m no big fan of Wordpress, so I’ve decided to move to <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> instead, hosted on the delightful <a href="https://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a>. This has a number of advantages, but it’s mostly just super easy to maintain, is very customisable, and is extremely minimal. This is a personal blog, not an all singing, all dancing corporate website.</p>

<p>I’m also inspired by the wonderful <a href="http://motherfuckingwebsite.com/">Motherfucking website</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <ul>
    <li>Shit’s lightweight and loads fast</li>
    <li>Fits on all your shitty screens</li>
    <li>Looks the same in all your shitty browsers</li>
    <li>The motherfucker’s accessible to every asshole that visits your site</li>
    <li>Shit’s legible and gets your fucking point across (if you had one instead of just 5mb pics of hipsters drinking coffee)</li>
  </ul>
</blockquote>

<p>All the old posts are backed up too, but I don’t expect anyone to read, or miss them. Me included.</p>
>
				</content>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.burythehammer.com/blog/new-beginnings</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.burythehammer.com/blog/new-beginnings</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
